<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<library>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="9304" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="Initiation into Philosophy" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="Emile Faguet" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1914" />
        <sample>
            The aim of philosophy is to seek the explanation of all
            things: the quest is for the first causes of everything, and also
            how all things are, and finally why, with what design, with a view
            to what, things are. That is why, taking "principle" in all the senses
            of the word, it has been called the science of first principles.
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="1998" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="Thus Spake Zarathustra" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="Friedrich Wilhelm Nietzsche" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1885" />
        <sample>
            When Zarathustra was thirty years old, he left his home and the lake of
            his home, and went into the mountains. There he enjoyed his spirit and
            solitude, and for ten years did not weary of it. But at last his heart
            changed, and rising one morning with the rosy dawn, he went before the
            sun, and spake thus unto it:
            Thou great star! What would be thy happiness if thou hadst not those 
            for whom thou shinest!       
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="4280" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="The Critique of Pure Reason" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="Immanuel Kant" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1781" />
        <sample>
            Human reason, in one sphere of its cognition, is called upon to
            consider questions, which it cannot decline, as they are presented
            by its own nature, but which it cannot answer, as they transcend every
            faculty of the mind.
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="5827" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="The Problems of Philosophy" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="Bertrand Russell" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1912" />
        <sample>
            Is there any knowledge in the world which is so certain that no 
            reasonable man could doubt it? This question, which at first sight
            might not seem difficult, is really one of the most difficult that 
            can be asked. When we have realized the obstacles in the way of a 
            straightforward and confident answer, we shall be well launched on 
            the study of philosophy—for philosophy is merely the attempt to 
            answer such ultimate questions, not carelessly and dogmatically, 
            as we do in ordinary life and even in the sciences, but critically, 
            after exploring all that makes such questions puzzling, and after 
            realizing all the vagueness and confusion that underlie our ordinary 
            ideas.        
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="5740" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="Tractatus Logico-Philosophicus" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="Ludwig Wittgenstein" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1921" />
        <sample>
            The book deals with the problems of philosophy, and shows, I believe, 
            that the reason why these problems are posed is that the logic of our 
            language is misunderstood. The whole sense of the book might be 
            summed up the following words: what can be said at all can be said 
            clearly, and what we cannot talk about we must pass over in silence.
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="4320" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="An Enquiry Concerning the Principles of Morals" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="David Hume" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1751" />
        <sample>
            DISPUTES with men, pertinaciously obstinate in their principles, 
            are, of all others, the most irksome; except, perhaps, those with 
            persons, entirely disingenuous, who really do not believe the 
            opinions they defend, but engage in the controversy, from 
            affectation, from a spirit of opposition, or from a desire of 
            showing wit and ingenuity, superior to the rest of mankind. The 
            same blind adherence to their own arguments is to be expected in 
            both; the same contempt of their antagonists; and the same 
            passionate vehemence, in inforcing sophistry and falsehood. 
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="11224" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="Utilitarianism" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="John Stuart Mill" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1863" />
        <sample>
            There are few circumstances among those which make up the present
            condition of human knowledge, more unlike what might have been 
            expected, or more significant of the backward state in which 
            speculation on the most important subjects still lingers, than the 
            little progress which has been made in the decision of the 
            controversy respecting the criterion of right and wrong. From the 
            dawn of philosophy, the question concerning the summum bonum, or, 
            what is the same thing, concerning the foundation of morality, 
            has been accounted the main problem in speculative thought, has 
            occupied the most gifted intellects, and divided them into sects 
            and schools, carrying on a vigorous warfare against one another.        
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="1232" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="The Prince" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="Niccolò Machiavelli" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1532" />
        <sample>
            All states, all powers, that have held and hold rule over men have 
            been and are either republics or principalities.

            Principalities are either hereditary, in which the family has been 
            long established; or they are new.

            The new are either entirely new, as was Milan to Francesco Sforza, 
            or they are, as it were, members annexed to the hereditary state of
            the prince who has acquired them, as was the kingdom of Naples to 
            that of the King of Spain.

            Such dominions thus acquired are either accustomed to live under a 
            prince, or to live in freedom; and are acquired either by the arms 
            of the prince himself, or of others, or else by fortune or by ability.
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="61" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="The Communist Manifesto" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="Friedrich Engels and Karl Marx" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1848" />
        <sample>
            The history of all hitherto existing societies is the history
            of class struggles.

            Freeman and slave, patrician and plebeian, lord and serf,
            guild-master and journeyman, in a word, oppressor and oppressed,
            stood in constant opposition to one another, carried on an
            uninterrupted, now hidden, now open fight, a fight that each time
            ended, either in a revolutionary re-constitution of society at
            large, or in the common ruin of the contending classes.
        </sample>
    </book>
    <book>
        <metadata name="ETextNo" value="16712" />
        <metadata name="Title" value="Some Turns of Thought in Modern Philosophy" />
        <metadata name="Author" value="George Santayana" />
        <metadata name="Year" value="1933" />
        <sample>
        In Locke the central presuppositions, which he embraced heartily and
        without question, were those of common sense. He adopted what he calls a
        "plain, historical method", fit, in his own words, "to be brought into
        well-bred company and polite conversation".
        </sample>
    </book>
</library>    
